we have six o'clock so i will call the march meeting of the historic architectural review board to order just by way of brief introduction the harb is a recommending board so the actions that are taken here this evening will then be moved on to city council who will ultimately act on on harb's recommendation and that will likely be at the march 11th 2025 meeting each member of the committee is utilizes the secretary of the interior standards in terms of review of the projects and and we're bound by those guidelines in reviewing what's before us in terms of a process we'd ask the applicant to come up to the table um have suzanne read or summarize her review of the project um have any questions um from the board and then open it up if there's any public that has questions so the first item on the agenda is 307 south lime street stephen uh evan golista owner evangelista i'm sorry thank you and it's replacement of a multi-light picture window with aluminum storefront window on the the facade of commercial building so yeah that way you can use why don't you if the table and then if you please make sure you turn your mic on and I'll remind the board members to to use your mics please
was installed in 1979 and the building was used by a metal working business or a tin shop that advertised early american lighting reproductions while relating to the tin shop business and its colonial theme picture window does not relate to the age and style of this utilitarian building which was built in about 1925 as a garage or auto repair shop the proposed storefront window will be an appropriate modern alteration that is more in keeping with the building's form and style and this interview references standards number two nine and ten thank you suzanne do you have
anything you'd like to add to the by way of explanation or no she covered a well it's just
an existing window that has some there's previous water damage around the window that that's since been repaired so there's kind of rust on the interior of it they can kind of see from the outside so that's kind of the reason for the replacement okay all right thank you are there
any questions or comments from the board just the one comment um suzanne this is really not so much about the proposed window but about the mention of change in signage yeah will that have
to come before mr evangelista he does not because he's it's the business doesn't have a lot of walking customers he's just using his warehouse he doesn't have any signage plan to be mounted on the exterior which you would review if he just has a decal or something on the inside window or door that would not be review okay you want to mount a sign on the wall or a bracket okay it's
good enough for the future yeah we don't have any plans of that but you're saying if we do want to do something in the future that's kind of revisit that okay good enough okay thank you no it seems
rather straightforward uh suzanne thank you very much for your um uh for your review uh mr chairman i recommend that city council hold on i'm sorry are there are there any comments from the public oh yes right mr chairman i recommend the city council approved certificate of appropriateness for the proposed alteration at 307 south line street to replace an existing multi-light picture window on the facade of a commercial building with a conier aluminum storefront window to feature a dark bronze finish per the submitted proposal this work meets the secretary of interior standards number two nine and ten i will make one note on that i know it
says dark bronze but they kind of came and gave us the quote to match the existing bronze color it'll be black if that's okay yeah I just wanted to make note of that so
there's no questions
okay so we have a motion is there a second discussion on the motion I guess
we'll clarify in terms of the finish we don't really comment on color but this would be finished okay thank you thank you administrative approvals were in your packet we've got 16 South Lime Street installation of new rubber roofing on a flat roof surprise that one even falls under our review can you see the roof yeah okay okay 229 Church Street in kind replacement of asphalt roof shingles 220 Howard Avenue in kind replacement of asphalt roof shingles 429 Church Street in kind replacement of cedar shake roof and cedar siding that's great 208 North Concord Street in like-kind replacement of steel door with sidelight with recessed entryway and 107 Howard Avenue replacement of one over one wooden windows on the facade following a violation notice after vinyl sash was installed without a permit so that's good to see too are there any questions on the administrative rules okay hearing none those will be part of the record minutes from December 3rd were there any questions or corrections on those move the minutes be accepted as presented okay we have a motion is there a second okay all those in favor please say aye aye thank you other business election of officers election of chair and vice chair for 2025. there wouldn't be any harm in postponing that we'd have the full group here in case somebody was feeling excited yeah right what postponed okay all right all right so we'll postpone that and then assignment of a board member to take part in the march 11th uh city council meeting which i don't think we need to worry about right so the only other item under other business i we hadn't been together for a while so it hasn't been in front of my thoughts but we do need to find the broker so just to discuss that in the public meeting that the board is down the real estate professional they do need to be a broker so um if the if the folks here can think of other folks that uh would have property in the city right they just have to serve the city oh that's good to know okay yeah and uh i
had made a recommendation just a connection to suzanne a couple of months ago and i think that that conversation is ongoing so okay hopefully we'll we have one prospect yep okay that seemed pretty excited about it they don't live in lancaster but they are a broker and they've been very interested in historic preservation in general the topic uh for quite some time so
okay all right thank you for that does anybody else have any other business then we will adjourn at 608 which may be one of our best ones all right thanks everybody thank you thank you